<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<article title="Introduction" author="wedge">

<!-- ----+---------+---------+---------+---------+---------+---------+----- -->
<content>

<p>
<strong>wmg</strong> is a Perl-based system primarily aimed at generating 
documents in XHTML format, together with any supporting data (e.g. images). 
Typical uses include generating web sites and product documentation (including 
the document you are reading now). The system is driven by a set of 
<em>templates</em>, which pick sections from input <em>articles</em> to 
produce output <em>documents</em>. By default these are in XHTML format, but,
by using different sets of templates, anything is possible. 
</p>

<pre>
                |---------|   
                | ARTICLE | 
                | -XML    |
                | -images |
                |         |
                |---------|   
                | ARTICLE | 
                |  -XML   |
                 \       /
                  \-----/
                   \   /
      TEMPLATES     \ /       OUTPUT
      XML+perl ---- wmg ----> XHTML...
</pre>

<h2>Source</h2>

<p>
This lives under the <em>src</em> directory, and contains:
</p>

<ul>
  <li>
  Articles - These XML files contain the textual content of the pages in XHTML,
  as well as other metadata, wrapped in a simple XML format. They can contain 
  embedded perl commands, using the &lt;?WMG ... ?&gt; syntax.
  </li>
  <li>
  Source data - Data in its original form, which needs to be transformed in 
  some way to produce the output. An example of this would be images, which 
  need to be resized and have thumbnails produced for incorporating into an 
  image gallery.
  </li>
</ul>

<p>
There are two ways in which articles can be stored - in <em>hierarchical</em> 
format and in <em>chronological</em> format. These can be used together if
required. In <em>hierarchical</em> format, an article specifies 
</p>

<h2>Templates</h2>

<p>
These live in the <em>tpl</em> directory, and contain instructions for 
transforming the source articles into the output documents. If an article does
not specify which template to use, "default.wmg" is selected. Template files 
can include other template files, which allow common page elements to be 
maintained. A set of standard templates are supplied with 
<strong>wmg</strong>, which are used if one is not found in the site's 
<em>tpl</em> directory.
</p>

<h2>Output</h2>

<p>
This is placed under the <em>html</em> directory, and contains the output 
documents and data produced by <strong>wmg</strong>.
</p>

</content>

</article>
